MIKE NEUDER.

(719) $659 \cdot 3861 \Leftrightarrow michael.neuder@gmail.com \Leftrightarrow Personal Webpage$

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A computer science and math undergraduate studying at University of Colorado at Boulder. I am fascinated by the use of machine learning, mathematical models, and computational science to predict and analyze the behavior of complex systems. I have a solid mathematical and computational background, as well as passion for learning and discovery that allows me to adapt quickly to a variety of research and industrial areas.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder

Aug 2015-Present

B.A. in Computer Science

B.A. in Mathematics

Expected Graduation: May 2019

Deans List & Sewell Esteemed Scholars Award

CU Data Science Team Member

Overall GPA: 3.82 - Computer Science GPA: 3.97

University of Oxford, Oxford

Jan 2018-June 2018

Visiting student at Mansfield College Hilary and Trinity Terms of 2018

Coursework in Probability, Graph Theory, and Economics

EXPERIENCE

Lab of Dr. Michael Mozer

March 2017 - Present

Boulder, CO

- · Developed neural networks using word processing and language analysis to predict reading behavior.
- · Synthesized data to train complex networks on a range of tasks.
- · Built classifiers and clustering analysis tools using to train models on unlabeled data.
- · Created several convolutional neural networks to replicate the Structural Similarity (SSIM) score of sets of images in order to embody a more accurate image quality evaluation metric.

Lab of Dr. Elizabeth Bradley

Research Assistant

Research Assistant

March 2017 - Present Boulder, CO

- · Used information theoretic measures of weighted and non-weighted permutation entropy to analyze the information produced by the climate system through water isotopic data collected in ice cores.
- · Compared accumulation and weighted permutation entropy to evaluate the relationship between the two values.
- · Wrote code in Python to create plots and time series graphs, as well as organize the data and run entropy calculations.
- · Analyzed how adjusting parameters in the permutation entropy calculation impacted the correlation coefficient between permutation entropy and accumulation.

Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space Physics / Lockheed Martin Feb 2017 - Nov 2017 Software Engineering Intern Boulder, CO

· Joint CU Boulder and Lockheed program in which CU students are trained at LASP to work at Lockheed when they receive security clearances.

- · Developed graphical applications using Python and C++ Qt Libraries.
- · Wrote interactive terminal applications using Perl and the Curses Module.
- · Developed graphical application testing suites using Eggplant Functional and SenseTalk.

Spire Manufacturing Solutions

 $Manufacturing\ Intern$

May 2014 - Aug 2014 Colorado Springs, CO

- · Operated CNC lathes and mills to manufacture metal components.
- · Inspected parts to verify measurements matched specifications prior to shipping the parts.
- · Repaired electric discharge machine and programmed machine to cut a custom part.

OTHER PROJECTS

Image Quality Analysis
Numerical Experiments
Rubik's Cube Solver
Python vs C++
she
Connect Four
Hack CU 2017

Code written for machine learning and image analysis research. A series of numerical analysis experiments written in python.

Wrote a program in C++ that solves a cube from any scrambled position.

Created benchmark runtimes of programs in both languages.

Wrote a web application with Ruby on Rails to simulate a virtual girlfriend.

Created a graphical implementation of the game in PyQt.

Took part in hackathon and modeled the spread of infectious disease.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages (Experienced) Programming Languages (Proficient) Libraries Tools Python, C++, Perl Ruby, R, Javascript, Matlab, bash, Java numpy, scipy, matplotlib, tensorflow, scikit-learn, Qt git VCS, LaTeX, Linux, Jupyter Notebooks